[{"id":1,"question":"1. What dog saved the lives of 40 people while working for monks (1800-1810) at a travelers way station at the 8,100 foot high Great Saint Bernard Pass in the Alps?","isMultipleChoiceQuestion":true,"explanation":"In 1810, Barry retired to to Berne, Switzerland. The way station continues to honor their most famous Saint Bernard by making sure that there is always one dog in the kennel named \"Barry\". A statue in honor of Barry may still be viewed in Paris, France, but is inaccurately inscribed, \"He saved the lives of 40 persons. He was killed by the 41st\". A legend had sprung up that Barry was killed in error by the last person he tried to rescue, which is perpetuated by this erroneous inscription. Finally, if you would like to visit Barry himself his remains are on display at Berne\u0027s Natural History Museum.","itemId":1,"answers":[{"id":1,"answer":"Barry.","isCorrect":true},{"id":2,"answer":"Gelert.","isCorrect":false},{"id":3,"answer":"Checkers.","isCorrect":false},{"id":4,"answer":"Greyfriars Bobby.","isCorrect":false}]},{"id":2,"question":"2. Being adopted by Albany, New York postal employees as a puppy Owney (1888-1897) began traveling with mail carriers on their delivery routes, wagons, railways, and eventually even went on a 113 day world tour sponsored by the USPS. Due to having traveled an estimated 114,000 miles with post office personnel it\u0027s not surprising that Owney is recognized as the mascot for what organization?","isMultipleChoiceQuestion":true,"explanation":"Postal workers used to award Owney tags and/or medals when he visited, which resulted in John Wannamaker, Postmaster General, having a harness custom made to display them on. Of course, over time even the harness could not accommodate the hundreds of medals Owney had acquired.\n\nUpon Owney\u0027s death postal employees raised money to have his remains preserved for posterity. Those wishing to remember Owney may find him today wearing his harness and medals at the National Postal Museum in Washington, D. C.\n\n\nTREAT YOURSELF TO A FILM \"The Story of Owney\" AT THE SMITHSONIAN LINK BELOW:\n\nhttp://www.postalmuseum.si.edu/exhibits/2c1f_owney_movie.html","itemId":1,"answers":[{"id":5,"answer":"New York Transit Authority.","isCorrect":false},{"id":6,"answer":"Travelers Insurance.","isCorrect":false},{"id":7,"answer":"Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals.","isCorrect":false},{"id":8,"answer":"United States Postal Service.","isCorrect":true}]},{"id":3,"question":"3. During World War I, an American Pit Bull Terrier named \"Stubby\" of the 102nd Infantry Division was awarded the rank of sergeant for which of the following acts of valor?","isMultipleChoiceQuestion":true,"explanation":"Stubby captured a German forward observer by flushing him out, chasing him down, and clamping his jaws on the soldier\u0027s buttocks until he was taken into custody by members of the 102nd Infantry Division.\n\nStubby performed all of the actions listed in the answer choices, but received his rank of sergeant specifically for the capture of the German forward observer.\n\nSgt. Stubby returned a hero to the U.S. with his companion Pvt. John Robert Conroy of the 102nd Infantry Division. Sgt. Stubby met President Roosevelt, was inducted into the American Legion, and was awarded a Humane Society medal from the leader of the American Expeditionary Forces, Gen. Joseph \"Black Jack\" Pershing.","itemId":1,"answers":[{"id":9,"answer":"Capturing a German forward observer.","isCorrect":true},{"id":10,"answer":"Sniffing out wounded troops and leading them to safety and/or summoning help.","isCorrect":false},{"id":11,"answer":"Participating in more than a dozen battles.","isCorrect":false},{"id":12,"answer":"Warning soldiers of poison gas.","isCorrect":false}]},{"id":4,"question":"4. In 1925, which Siberian Husky traveled through -70 degree temperatures, near whiteout conditions, and gale force winds for 91 miles to relay serum for use in combating a diptheria epidemic in Nome, Alaska?","isMultipleChoiceQuestion":true,"explanation":"Togo traveled with his team led by Edward Seppala 170 miles across Alaska just to pick up the serum and then made the 91 mile run to hand off the serum to the next musher in the relay. Although Balto is more readily remembered due to the fact he and his team under Gunnar Kaasen actually delivered the serum they had only traveled 53 miles in comparison to the total of 261 miles traveled by Seppala\u0027s team.\n\nOn a previous trip across Norton Sound Seppala and his team were marooned on an ice floe. Nearing land (but not close enough to gain purchase) Seppala picked up Togo wearing his harness and braces and threw him across the gap to land. Togo began to pull with the goal of bringing the ice floe close enough to land for Seppala and the team to cross. The lead snapped, which Seppala said denoted a death sentence. Togo taking the initiative jumped into the icy water and returned to land with the lead in his mouth. After rolling around to wrap the lead around himself Togo pulled the ice floe to land thereby saving Seppala and his team.*\n\n\n* An additional reference to the overall reference at the end of the quiz:\n\nSalisbury, Gay \u0026 Salisbury Laney (2003). The Cruelest Miles. W. W. Norton \u0026 Company, Inc., New York, NY.","itemId":1,"answers":[{"id":13,"answer":"Togo.","isCorrect":true},{"id":14,"answer":"Balto.","isCorrect":false},{"id":15,"answer":"Alaska Slim.","isCorrect":false},{"id":16,"answer":"Moctoc.","isCorrect":false}]},{"id":5,"question":"5. Jim (1925-1937), a Llewelyn setter, was dubbed the \"Wonder Dog\" by his hometown of Marshall, Missouri for being able perform which of the following tasks?","isMultipleChoiceQuestion":true,"explanation":"Jim\u0027s extraordinary abilities were exhibited before a joint session of Missouri legislators and a panel of professors at the University of Missouri. As reported by the Rural Missouri magazine the professors were so impressed that they told the crowd that, \"Jim possessed an occult power that might never come again to a dog in many generations\".\n\nToday visitors to Marshall, Missouri that wish to remember Jim can visit his grave at Ridge Park Cemetery or the Wonder Dog Memorial Park located downtown.","itemId":1,"answers":[{"id":17,"answer":"Identify cars by being told the plate number.","isCorrect":false},{"id":18,"answer":"Read messages.","isCorrect":false},{"id":19,"answer":"Identify people by being told their physical characteristics.","isCorrect":false},{"id":20,"answer":"All of the answers are correct.","isCorrect":true}]},{"id":6,"question":"6. At Tokyo\u0027s Shibuya train station a statue honors an Akita dog, Hachiko, that visited the train station every day at 3 o\u0027clock for around ten years (1925-1935) in anticipation of what event?","isMultipleChoiceQuestion":true,"explanation":"Eisaburo Ueno was the professor that Hachiko so loved that he accompanied him to the train station every morning to see him off to work at the University of Tokyo\u0027s Agricultural Department. Conversely, Hachiko eagerly awaited his master\u0027s return in the afternoon and must have known that when Ueno didn\u0027t return it was because something was keeping him from returning. As word of Hachiko\u0027s love and devotion spread across Japan he became a national icon immortalized in the media, books, and a bronze statue of which he was present at the unveiling.","itemId":1,"answers":[{"id":21,"answer":"Chasing commuters off the platform.","isCorrect":false},{"id":22,"answer":"The return of his deceased master.","isCorrect":true},{"id":23,"answer":"Howling with the train whistle.","isCorrect":false},{"id":24,"answer":"Unloading of fresh fish.","isCorrect":false}]},{"id":7,"question":"7. Bamse, a Saint Bernard, served with the Free Norwegian Forces on the ship \"Thorrud\" stationed in Dundee and Montrose, Scotland during World War II and is noted for having performed which of the following deeds?","isMultipleChoiceQuestion":true,"explanation":"Bamse was a national hero in Norway during WWII and was featured both on Christmas cards sent to Norweigan soldiers and during the May 17 Constitution Day celebration. When Bamse died of undetermined causes in Montrose, Scotland there was a period of deep mourning with businesses closing for his funeral. During the funeral procession approximately 800 children lined the route to Bamse\u0027s grave near the sea where he was buried facing Norway.\n\nIn 2006, Bamse was honored with a bronze statue erected in Montrose, Scotland. During the same year Bamse was also awarded the prestigious Gold Medal for his wartime service by Britain\u0027s People\u0027s Dispensary for Sick Animals.","itemId":1,"answers":[{"id":25,"answer":"All of the choices are correct.","isCorrect":true},{"id":26,"answer":"Shoved a knife wielding assailant off a dock to save a fellow sailor.","isCorrect":false},{"id":27,"answer":"Spontaneously saved at least one sailor from drowning.","isCorrect":false},{"id":28,"answer":"Traveled by bus on his own to neighboring towns to track down errant crew members.","isCorrect":false}]},{"id":8,"question":"8. Bothie, a Jack Russell Terrier, accompanied Sir Ranulf and Lady Virginia Fiennes on the Transglobe Expedition (1979-1982) to circumnavigate the planet making him the first dog to visit which pole(s)?","isMultipleChoiceQuestion":true,"explanation":"During the Transglobe Expedition Bothie was tethered by harness to the ship deck during rough weather and embarassingly enough had to suit up in custom made caps, booties, and stockings in cold weather environments. However, he became a celebrity and was awarded the Great Britain\u0027s Pet of the Year Award (1982). Also, Bothie met the love of his life in the Yukon a huge Newfoundland-Husky-Labrador mix named \"Black Dog\". The happy couple subsequently set up house (living without benefit of matrimony) in Great Britain.","itemId":1,"answers":[{"id":29,"answer":"North Pole.","isCorrect":false},{"id":30,"answer":"None of the choices are correct.","isCorrect":false},{"id":31,"answer":"South Pole.","isCorrect":false},{"id":32,"answer":"North and South Poles.","isCorrect":true}]},{"id":9,"question":"9. On September 11, 2001, a four year old Labrador retriever named \"Dorado\" insisted on spending one hour guiding his blind master down 70 floors of the north tower of what building?","isMultipleChoiceQuestion":true,"explanation":"Dorado\u0027s companion, Omar Eduardo Rivera, was working at the World Trade Center as a computer technician on 9/11 when the north tower was hit by a highjacked airline. Amid the panic and smoke Omar unleashed Dorado, so that at least one of them would have the chance of escaping the building. Dorado left for a few minutes and then came back to Omar and nudged him toward an exit. By chance Omar\u0027s boss was passing as they emerged, so between the efforts of Dorado and the boss they were all three able to make it out of the building and were a few blocks away before the building collapsed.","itemId":1,"answers":[{"id":33,"answer":"Bank of America Tower.","isCorrect":false},{"id":34,"answer":"Flatiron Building.","isCorrect":false},{"id":35,"answer":"Empire State Building.","isCorrect":false},{"id":36,"answer":"World Trade Center","isCorrect":true}]},{"id":10,"question":"10. On February 6, 2006, a Beagle named \"Belle\" was unsuccessful in making her master understand that his blood sugar level was dangerously low. When Kevin Weaver inevitably collapsed due to low blood sugar what did Belle do to save his life?","isMultipleChoiceQuestion":true,"explanation":"Belle received 9 months of medical assistant training that cost $9000.00. One of the things she was trained to do if Kevin became totally incapacitated was to punch the number \"9\" on the telephone. This action resulted in the automatic dialing of 911 for medical assistance. Subsequently, when emergency hit Belle had to find Kevin\u0027s mobile telephone, bite the \"9\", wait for contact with the operator, which once established she began barking nonstop in a hysterical fashion until the ambulance arrived. After his recovery Kevin Weaver told the Associated Press, \"Belle is more than a lifesaver, she\u0027s my best friend\". Truer words were never spoken.\n\n\nReference Applying to Entire Quiz:\n\nStall, Sam (2007). 100 Dogs who Changed Civilization: History\u0027s Most Influential Canines. Quirk Productions, Inc., Philadelphia, PA.","itemId":1,"answers":[{"id":37,"answer":"Administered an insulin shot.","isCorrect":false},{"id":38,"answer":"Called 911.","isCorrect":true},{"id":39,"answer":"Administered hard candies orally.","isCorrect":false},{"id":40,"answer":"Barked until a human being arrived to render assistance.","isCorrect":false}]}]